Track 1 doesn't score you on what your
agent can do. It scores you on how few
tokens it needs to do it — while staying
accurate. Most teams will point every task
at the biggest model and call it done.
That's the expensive way.
Our routing agent asks one question before
it ever calls an LLM: does this task
actually need one? A regex-and-AST
classifier catches arithmetic, date math,
string ops, unit conversion, and
extraction — and solves them for zero
tokens. Everything else goes to the
cheapest model that can handle it, gated
by a confidence check. Only tasks that
fail that gate escalate — once — to the
strongest model. No retries loop, no
self-verification tax.
Watch the route field. 'What is 847 times
36' — that's real arithmetic, correctly
answered, zero Fireworks tokens spent. No
model was called. In our 200-task eval
set, 65 tasks — just under a third —
resolve exactly this way.
This one needs a model — it's sentiment
classification. The router picks the
cheapest model that's adequate for the
job, gpt-oss-20b, with a minimal prompt,
temperature zero, and reasoning suppressed
so it doesn't burn completion tokens
thinking out loud. Notice the token count
— small, and it's what actually gets
billed, not an estimate.
Every call — Tier 0 or Tier 1 — updates a
running ledger: raw tokens, price-weighted
cost, and route distribution. That's the
same ledger the eval harness uses to score
the full 200-task run.
Across the full 200-task eval set: 99.5%
accuracy — 199 out of 200 correct.
Thirty-two and a half percent of tasks
never touch a model at all. And against an
honest baseline — same tasks, strongest
model, no routing tricks — total token
spend drops by roughly 47 to 51%. The
whole run costs a third of a cent and
finishes in under 24 seconds.
One more thing: the model registry
auto-prefers Gemma at equal price tier
whenever the harness allows it — that's
unit-tested and ready today. On July 7th,
when we probed the live Fireworks account,
Gemma wasn't exposed on serverless, so
this run routes through gpt-oss and
DeepSeek instead. The preference activates
automatically the moment Gemma becomes
available — no code change needed. Routing
intelligence, not raw compute. That's the
whole pitch.